Van Chan Ngo

School of Computer Science Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA 15213, USA

Email: channgo@cmu.edu

URL: http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~vanchann/

Current Position

Post-doctoral Researcher, Principles of Programming Languages, School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, USA

Areas of Specialization

Programming Languages • Formal Verification • Compilers

Research Interests

My research activities aim at building reliable and secure computer systems by developing formal frameworks which guarantee that software satisfies formally its specification, especially embedded safety-critical software such as automotive, avionic, and health-care applications. The construction of a formal framework involves the research and knowledge of principles of programming languages, compiler design and development, and formal methods including model checking, theorem proving, and static analysis, to provide formal assurances that the specification is fulfilled.

Education

Ph.D in Computer Science, INRIA Rennes-Bretagne Atlantique and Université de Rennes 1, Rennes, France, 08/2014

First Class Honors

MSc in Computer Science, Université Joseph Fourier, Grenoble, France, under a French Government Scholarship-06/2008

Évariste Galois

Engineer in Computer Engineering, Center of Talented Training-PFIEV, Hanoi University of Technology, 07/2005

Hanoi, Vietnam, First Class Honors with Congratulations of the Ministry of Education

Awards & Honors

Ph.D scholarship, INRIA France 2011-2014

DEA scholarship from the French government, Université de Grenoble, France 2007-2008 2007 Masters scholarship from the Italian government, Politecnico di Milano, Italy Masters scholarship from SamSung company, ICU-KAIST, South Korea 2207

Scholarships from Hanoi University of Technology for excellent academic results 2000-2005

Employment History

2016-Present Research Fellow, School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, USA

- · Automatic symbolic resource bound (e.g., time and memory) analysis of functional and imperative programs for detecting security vulnerability including time side-channel attacks, stack overflow, etc
- · Static analysis for probabilistic programs, e.g., automatic symbolic expected resource bound analysis such as execution time and memory usage

Research Engineer, INRIA, Rennes, France

Research Assistant, INRIA, Rennes, France

- Formal verification of probabilistic SystemC models using Statistical Model Checking
- Probabilistic temporal assertion-based verification of SystemC models
- · Formal verification of the highly optimizing and industrial synchronous compiler, Signal, which is used in model-based design of real-time and safety-critical systems
 - Using translation validation approach to prove the preservation of clock semantics, data dependencies and

1

2015-2016

2011-2014

value-equivalence for source code and the compiled programs using several techniques including model checking, theorem proving, and graph transformation

Software Architect, Tech Propulsion Lab, USA 2010-2011

- · Design and development of embedded mobile software on iOS and Android platforms
- Project management in the mobile development department

Research Assistant, IBM Zurich Lab and ZISC, Zurich, Switzerland 2008-2009

- · Formally verifying and certifying the design of secure boot processes in IBM AIX mainframes
- · Formalizing the boot process and its security properties using the language of the model checker Spin,

Internship, VERIMAG Laboratory, Grenoble, France

- · Automated verification framework for formally proving the IND-CPA security property of asymmetric encryption schemes
- Representing the encryption schemes as frames in cryptographic π -calculus, and formalizing the IND-CPA property as a equivalent relation between two frames

Senior Software Engineer, IBM, Hanoi, Vietnam

- Working on text search engine of the IBM data base management DB2
- Software Engineer, FPT Software, Hanoi, Vietnam • Working on embedded systems for navigation

Technical Strengths

• Strong knowledge: C/C++, OCaml • Familiarity: Assembly, Java, Python Programming

Languages

• Strong knowledge: GCC, LLVM Compiler Infrastructure

• Strong knowledge: Synchronous Programming, Logics and Temporal Logics, Model Checking, Theorem Formal Meth-

ods & Model-Proving, Static Analysis • Familiarity: SystemC, Verilog ing Languages

Formal Method • Strong knowledge: SPIN, SMV, UPAAL, PRISM, SMC Plasma Lab, Yices, Z3, Coq, Frama-C

Tools

Embedded Soft- • Familiarity: AVR, Arduino, RTLinux, FreeRTOS

ware Develop-

Languages

• English: Advance • French: Advance • Vietnamese: Native

Publications

Journal & Conference

V.C. Ngo, Q. Carbonneaux, and J. Hoffmann. Bounded Expectations: Resource Analysis for Probabilistic Programs. In Submission to 2018 ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI'18). ACM, Philadelphia, PA, USA [PDF]

V.C. Ngo, M. Dehesa-Azuara, M. Fredrikson, J. Hoffmann. Verifying and Synthesizing Constant-Resource Implementations with Types. To appear in 2017 IEEE Symposium on Security & Privacy (SP Oakland'17). IEEE, San Jose, CA, USA [PDF]

V.C. Ngo and A. Legay. Formal Verification of Probabilistic SystemC Models with Statistical Model Checking. 2017 In Journal of Software: Evolution and Process. Wiley [PDF]

V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and V. Joloboff. PSCV: A Runtime Verification Tool for Probabilistic SystemC Models. In 2016 Proceedings of 28th International Conference on Computer Aided Verification (CAV'16). Springer, Toronto, Ontario, Canada [PDF]

V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. Statistical Model Checking for SystemC Models. In Proceedings of 17th 2016 High Assurance Systems Engineering Symposium (HASE'16). IEEE, Orlando, Florida, USA [PDF]

V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, L. Besnard, and P. Le Guernic. Modular Translation Validation of a Full-sized Synchronous Compiler using Off-the-shelf Verification Tools. In Proceedings of International Workshop on Software and Compilers for Embedded Systems (SCOPES'15). ACM, St. Goar, Germany [PDF]

V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and T. Gautier. Translation Validation for Synchronous Data-flow Specification in the SIGNAL Compiler. In Proceedings of 35th IFIP International Conference on Formal Techniques for Distributed Objects, Components and Systems (FORTE'15). IFIP, Grenoble, France [PDF]

2

2007-2008

2006-2007

2005-2006

Toolchains

ment

2017

2017

2015

2015

- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, and P. Le Guernic. *Translation Validation for Clock Transformations in a Synchronous Compiler.* In Proceedings of 18th International Conference on Fundamental Approaches to Software Engineering (FASE'15). Springer, London, UK [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and T. Gautier. *Precise Deadlock Detection for Polychronous Data-flow Specifications*. In Proceedings of the Electronic System Level Synthesis Conference (**ESLsyn-DAC'14**). IEEE, San Francisco, CA, USA [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Synchronous Data-flow Program Transformations Toward Certified Compilers. In Journal of Frontiers of Computer Science. Special Issue on Synchronous Programming, Springer [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Automatically Generated C-code from Polychronous Data-flow Equations. Accepted at International High-Level Design, Validation and Test Workshop (HLDVT'12). IEEE, California, USA [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Compiler Transformations on Polychronous Equations. In Proceedings of 9th International Conference on Integrated Formal Methods (IFM'12). Springer, Pisa, Italy [PDF]
- C. Ene, Y. Lakhnech, and V.C. Ngo (Authors by alphabetical order). Formal Indistinguishability Extended to the Random Oracle Model. In Proceedings of 14th European Symposium on Research in Computer Security (ESORICS'09). Springer, Saint-Malo, France [PDF]
- C. Ene, Y. Lakhnech, and V.C. Ngo (Authors by alphabetical order). Formal Indistinguishability Extended to the ROM. In Proceedings of Workshop on Formal and Computational Cryptography (FCC'09), New York, USA [PDF]

Thesis

- V.C. Ngo. Formal Verification of a Synchronous Data-flow Compiler: from Signal to C. In Ph.D Thesis in Computer Science, INRIA France, University of Rennes 1, France [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo. *Automated Verification of Asymmetric Encryption.* In MSc Thesis in Computer Science and Applied Mathematics, VERIMAG, University of Grenoble, France [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo. Theory and Implementation of Distributed Firewall on Linux Environment (in Vietnamese). In Engineer Thesis in Computer Engineerings, Center for Talent Training, Hanoi University of Technology, Hanoi

Technical Report

- V.C. Ngo, Q. Carbonneaux, and J. Hoffmann. *Bounded Expectations: Resource Analysis for Probabilistic Programs.* In CMU, Technical Report [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, M. Fredrikson, and J. Hoffmann. *Quantifying and Preventing Side Channels with Substructural Type Systems.* In CMU, Technical Report [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. Dependability Analysis of Embedded Control Systems Using SystemC and Statistical Model Checking. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-8762 [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, A. Legay, and J. Quilbeuf. *Dynamic Verification of SystemC Specification with Statistical Model Checking*. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-8644 [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, and P. Le Guernic. Evaluating SDVG Translation Validation: from Signal to C. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-8508 [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, and P. Le Guernic. Formal Verification of Transformations on Abstract Clocks in Synchronous Compilers. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-8064 [PDF]
- V.C. Ngo, J-P. Talpin, T. Gautier, P. Le Guernic, and L. Besnard. Formal Verification of Synchronous Data-flow Compilers. In HAL-INRIA, Technical Report RR-7921 [PDF]

Talks

Academic Conference Presentations: Oakland 2017, CAV 2016, HASE 2016, FORTE 2015, FASE 2015, ESLsyn-DAC 2014, IFM 2012, ESORICS 2009

Invited Presentations: Dagtuhl Seminar 2017, INRIA Rennes 2015, Compilation 2014, Beihang University (BUAA) 2012, Synchron 2012

Software

Absynth Automatic Bound Synthesizer (Absynth) is a tool that automatically and statically computes upper bounds

on the expected resource usage for imperative probabilistic programs

RAML Resource Aware ML is a tool that automatically and statically computes bounds on resource usage (lower,

constant, and upper bounds) for functional programs. It also can check the constant resource-use programs

used in preventing timing side-channel attacks [HTML]

PSCV A runtime verification tool for probabilistic SystemC models. It consists of two components: the plug-in

for Plasma Lab in Java and tool for generating C++ monitor and aspect advices in C++ [HTML]

Plasma Lab Plasma Lab is a compact, efficient and flexible platform for statistical model checking of stochastic models

HTML]

Polychrony The Polychrony tool-set developed in C++ and Java, based on Signal, provides a formal framework to design,

develop and validate critical systems, from abstract specification until deployment on distributed systems

[HTML]

SigCert The tool developed in OCaml checks the correctness of the compilation of Signal compiler w.r.t clock se-

mantics, data dependence, and value-equivalence (not fully implemented) [HTML]

SigCV PDS Simulation Relation Checking with SIGALI: implementation of the theory works in IFM 2012 article as

the libraries in SIGALI tool-set [HTML]

Mobile Appli- Mobile applications: RATP, Turnstone, Saigon Places, A86, PhotoEnc,... [HTML]

cations

2012

Teaching

2016 Mechanizing Soundness Proofs of the Automatic Amortized Resource Analysis, Student project in Computer

Science, Carnegie Mellon University

2013 Introduction to Model Checking, Teaching assistant, Master in Computer Science, University of Rennes 1

Automaton-based Modeling and Formal Verification, Teaching assistant, Master in Computer Science, Uni-

versity of Rennes 1

2000-2003 High School Student Teaching in Mathematics and Physics, Tutor, Hanoi University of Technology

Professional Service

Review Activity: DICE 2018, TOPLAS 2018, CAV 2017, PLDI 2017, CC 2017, FMCAD 2016, CONCUR 2016, MEMOCODE 2015, LATA 2014

Research Projects

STAC[HTML], DANSE[HTML], DALI[HTML], VERISYNC[HTML], SCALP[HTML], AVOTE[HTML]